

André Leite Carvalho

Front-End Engineer

cavalho.devel@gmail.com +55 11 94924-5875

Profile

Front-End Developer with over 3 years of experience, dedicated to transforming innovative ideas into digital reality. Strong background TypeScript, JavaScript, React e React Navite.

Personal Information

Nationality: Brazilian

Location: São Paulo, Brazil

Date of Birth: July 20, 1998

Languages

Portuguese: Native

English: Intermediate

Contact

andrelcarvalho.netlify.app

/carvalhoandre

im /carvalhoandree

Professional Experience

Syndesi

April 2024 - Present

Front-End Engineer

Specialized in React with proficiency in JavaScript/TypeScript and functional programming practices as well as SOLID principles.

Experienced with agile methodologies, state management using Zustand, version control with Git and GitHub, consuming REST APIs, and solving technical challenges in a team environment.

Hyperlocal

March 2022 - April 2024

Front-End Developer

Developed and maintained web applications using React and TypeScript.

Implemented state management using Redux-Saga.

Ensured code quality with JEST and Cypress for testing.

Collaborated in agile teams (Scrum) to deliver high-quality software.

Proative Technology

August 2021 - March 2022

Front-End Developer

Actively participated in project conception and development with a focus on functional programming. Responsible for version control and repository management. Developed applications using React and React

Education

January 2018 - December 2022

São Paulo - SP

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Universidade Nove de Julho

Courses And Certifications

FrontEnd Development Course

Origamid

Focused on web development and are divided into two categories: Front End and UX/UI Design. Below are the main courses, followed by a list of the 22 available courses.

Certified Scrum Trainer (CST)

CertiProf

Certification ID: 62756068

Skills

Languages & Frameworks

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Native and Angular

State Management

Zustand, Redux-Saga and Redux Toolkit

Testing

JEST and Cypress

Version Control

Git, GitHub and Azure

Principles & Methodologies

SOLID, Functional Programming - Agile (Scrum)